Guide to the Washington State Council of Fire Fighters
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Washington State Council of Fire Fighters records
1914-1997
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6041
6041-001
Washington State Council of Fire Fighters
.66 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Materials related to the organization,Washington State Council of Fire Fighters
The Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) was founded on September 1, 1939, and represents 130 affiliated local fire fighter unions and more than 6900 affiliated members of the International Association of Fire Fighters (IAFF) within the state. The WSCFF’s mission is to provide the best possible working conditions, the safest work environment, and the fairest wages and benefits to fulfill the needs of the men and women in this profession. The council is active on local and national fronts with regard to issues that affect its members. The WSCFF administers several major programs in addition to political action. Education is provided through regional classes and one comprehensive educational seminar per year. An annual Convention is held to elect officers and determine policy and direction of the WSCFF. Legal assistance is provided through direct response financial loans or retention of counsel. Representation is provided when needed and requested for contract negotiations, mediation, interest arbitration, grievance arbitration, and other matters.
The WSCFF’s Board of Directors is made up of its executive officers and an elected representative from 11 geographic regions (WSCFF districts across the state). Since WSCFF and legislative districts are not the same, there is some overlap whereby WSCFF board members represent multiple legislative districts. The WSCFF is affiliated with the International Association of Fire Fighters (IAFF), American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), Washington State Labor Council (WSLC) and Canadian Labor Congress (CLC). (Source; WSCFF website www.wscff.org)
Conference files, subject files on legislation, bylaws of organization, and correspondence on activities of WSCFF.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
No restrictions on access.
Donated by the Labor Education and Research Center, South Seattle Community College, 2014-12-03
Washington State Council of Fire Fighters$vArchives.; Washington State Council of Fire Fighters$vCongresses.; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Fire fighters$xLabor unions$zWashington (State); Fire fighters$zWashington (State); Labor$zWashington (State); Business correspondence.; By-laws.; Records (Documents)
Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1963 Conference (Box-folder 1/1)
- Pension Laws, 1961 December 19 - 1962 September 24 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Requests for Shorter Work Weeks, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Treasurer's Reports and Financial Notes, 1962 June 1 - 1967 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1965 Conference, 1965 May 10 - 1965 November 18 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1966 Conference (Part 1 of 2), 1966 February - 1966 May (Box-folder 1/6)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1966 Conference (Part 2 of 2), 1966 June 20 - 1966 June 25 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Washington State Labor Relations Act rough draft, Undated (Box-folder 1/8)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1964 Conference, 1964 June 23 - 1964 November 9 (Box-folder 1/9)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1967 Conference, 1967 April 3 - 1967 Jume 22 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Copies of Newspaper Clippings on Firemen's Union, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 1/11)
- The Great Spokane Fire of 1889, 1889-1964 (Box-folder 1/12)
- Washington Professional Fire Fighter magazines, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 1/13)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1968 Conference (Part 1 of 2), 1968 April 15 - 1968 June 19 (Box-folder 2/1)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1968 Conference (Part 2 of 2), 1968 June 20 - 1968 December 18 (Box-folder 2/2)
- General Information on Unions, 1976 September - 1997 June (Box-folder 2/3)
- Washington State Council of Fire Fighters (WSCFF) 1969 Conference, 1969- 1963 (Box-folder 2/4)
- Proposed By-Laws, 1965 (Box-folder 2/5)
- Miscellaneous Notes, Undated (Box-folder 2/6)